Akmal Azami, Junior Front End Developer

London, United Kingdom, 07884375315, akmal@azami.io

LINKS	Portfolio, Github, LinkedIn, Redlight - AI-Powered Movie App, Traveller - Traveller - AI-Powered Travelling Map., Envio - Cloud Hosting Website, TJ Cheng - Asian Fine Dining			
PROFILE	I have 5 years of experience running start-ups right from the idea stage at the world's most connected tech community - Level39. Over these years, I have developed a strong passion for software development in particular front-end. Having taken an intensive web development course in one of the highest-ranked Bootcamps in Europe - Ironhack, and building several projects I have become a confident front-end developer. Currently, holding a part-time position as a Junior Developer at Fortu Wealth.			
	SKILLS	React	Redux	Material UI
JavaScript		RESTful API	Git	GitHub
Axios		Google APIs	JIRA	Figma
HTML		CSS	VSCode	Heroku

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Aug 2022 — Present

Front - End Developer (Part-Time), Fortu Wealth

London

Private Banking Solution for Affluent Individuals and their Businesses

Responsibilities:

- Updating and developing new **components** for the landing page
- Coding signed off design into working web page of the back office and communicating to back-end through protobuf
- Work closely with back-end developers and designers to deliver a consistent and reliable web experience

Apr 2019 — Mar 2022

Project manager | Finance officer, Fortu Wealth

London

- Participated in **every stage of development of the start-up** from the first spark of an idea to the release of the final product, raising funds and building team
- Led the Research and Development tax relief procedure and received $\pounds 134,\!000$ from HMRC
- · Managed liquidity and ensured delivery of projects according to the budget
- Managed and led the fundraising process of £1.3M by preparing a pitch deck and a financial model, organised investor events, drafted shareholder agreements

Jun 2017 — Present

Project manager | Finance officer, Jefferson Capital

London

App for Ultra High Net Worth clients and Portfolio Managers to track their global wealth in real-time.

- · Assisted senior management with developing a business plan, technical documentation plan, and budget
- Created user journey charts, designed sketches with intended functionalities for client app and admin panel for portfolio managers
- Developed key project goals and worked collaboratively with the teams to meet those goals using Agile Scrum methodologies

PROJECTS

Redlight - AI-powered Movie App

Redlight is an AI-powered Movie App built on React that lets the users search for the movies, see movie details, including cast, trailers, and websites, and get recommendations. Users can create an account and add movies to their watchlists.

 Used Redux for state management, as well as for fetching various data from The Movie API Database

- Performed GET request to fetch the data and POST request for adding/removing movies to/from watchlist within the usage of Axios
- Utilised Material UI components for the user interface as well as for implementing toggler event for dark and light mode
- Alan AI integrated to render the voice commands of the user for logging in/out, searching for the movies, changing the mode

Traveller - AI-powered travelling map website

Traveller is an AI-powered travelling map website built on React for finding restaurants, hotels and attractions based on the location of the user.

- Used **Google Maps API & Google Places API** to fetch data for the current location of the user, or for the location being searched for the purpose of features of geolocation
- Utilised the marketplace for API, RAPID API, to render the result based on the latitude and longitude of the user Integrated
- Alan AI for listening to voice commands and rendering the result
- Material UI components were utilised for the user interface of the website

Envio - cloud hosting website

Envio is a cloud hosting website built using pure HTML and CSS.

- The responsive website was built using the mobile-first approach using the BEM convention to make the code more readable and cleaner
- The images and fonts were optimised for performance

EDUCATION

Front-End Web Development, Bootcamps

- Took intensive web development course in one of the highest-ranked Bootcamps in Europe Ironhack
- · Covered Front-End topics in more depth at Code with Mosh is one of the top-ranked online courses
- Free Coding Camp have practised exercises to sharpen my knowledge
- Please check the portfolio for the projects built after the completion of the courses and Bootcamp
- Topics covered: React JS, JavaScript, Redux, Axios, Bootstrap, Material UI, HTML, CSS

Oct 2021 Professional Diploma in Accounting, AAT

Jun 2019 BSc (Hons) in Economics and Finance, Queen Mary University of

London

LANGUAGES English Highly proficient Tajik Native speaker

Russian Highly proficient Persian Highly proficient

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Mar 2020 Peshraft Charity Organisation

Front-End Developer and Fundraising Volunteer

Jan 2016 — Jun 2019 Queen Mary University of London

Course Representative Award and Skills Award

Founder & President of Entrepreneurs' Society

HOBBIES

Hiking | Camping | Tennis | Mixed Martial Arts